novanym.com 2016-03-16

# Privacy policy – Novanym

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally identifiable information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**  
When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number or other details to help you with your experience.

**When do we collect information?**  
We collect information from you when you place an order, subscribe to a newsletter or enter information on our site.

**How do we use your information?**  
We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To process your transactions.
  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.

We will never pass your details on to any third party.

**How do we protect visitor information?**  
Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

**Transactions**  
No sensitive/credit information you supply is recorded or collected by us. All transactions are processed through secure third party gateway providers (Stripe.com and Paypal.com) and are never stored or processed on our servers.

**We use 'cookies'**  
Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. We also use cookies to help us compile anonymous data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies, the shopping cart may not function properly, but your experience of using the rest of the site should not be affected. 

**Third Party Disclosure**  
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information.

**Third party links**  
We do not include or offer third party products or services on our website.

**Google**  
Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en

We have implemented Google AdSense remarketing on our site.

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

Opting out: Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

**Email  
** We collect your email address when we process orders, or when you subscribe to receive updates from us. If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at hello@novanym.com, or click 'unsubscribe' at the bottom of our newsletter emails. We will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence. In the unlikely event of a data breach, we will notify users via email within two business days.

**Contacting Us  
** If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

hello@novanym.com

Novanym Limited registered office:  
Sherwood House, Farnborough, Hampshire GU14 6JP United Kingdom
